



Sarfaraz Ali

Nationality: Pakistani Date of birth: 14/04/1997 Gender: Male

○ WhatsApp Messenger: +923052090559

Skype: https://join.skype.com/invite/yUXJOs8xeDPM

WeChat: wxid ovotyaxvysdo22

f Facebook: https://web.facebook.com/sarfaraz.memon.560/

in LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sarfaraz-ali-14bb90202

Home: Village Mari Taluka Lakhi District Shikarpur, Sindh, 78100 Shikarpur (Pakistan

)

ABOUT ME

My professional ambition is to cultivate a reputation as a congenial companion, compassionate spouse, dedicated individual, and approachable parent. Armed with a Masters (M.Phil.) degree in applied linguistics, I bring to the table five years of teaching expertise garnered from my tenure at a private English language center. I have also contributed my skills as a Tutor at the Global Peace Institute in London, as a Trainer at the World Youth Alliance and English lecturer at different schools, colleges and universities.

Furthermore, my commitment to personal and professional development is evident in my completion of an internship at the World Youth Alliance Asia Pacific and the recent accolade of a Gold Medal from the Global Peace Institute in London. Noteworthy is my open-mindedness, coupled with a penchant for creative, modern, and innovative thinking.

My pursuit of continuous improvement is demonstrated through participation in various training sessions, short courses, and summits conducted by regional, national, and international institutions. This commitment extends to both virtual and physical platforms. In addition to my academic achievements, I boast a proficiency in Information Technology, having successfully completed short courses such as M.S Office, Certification in Information Technology (CIT), Diploma in Information Technology (D.I.T), Hardware, Digital Literacy, Economics and Business International Camp and Courses for Sustainability (EBICCS), New Trends in Language and Linguistics Studies (International Academic Conference on Corpus Linguistics), Understanding Indonesian's Face through Tourism Destination Rebranding, Certified Training Program (CTP), Certified Peace Educator, Diplomacy Academy, M4M Volunteer Training Program, Advocacy Academy, Emotional CPR, Compassion Integrity Training (CIT), and Regional Peer Education.

In totality, I am eager to apply my wealth of knowledge, techniques, and skills in a dynamic and challenging environment. I am enthusiastic about assimilating modern, progressive, and liberal ideas during my tenure with your esteemed organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

English Lecturer

IBA Community College [01/09/2023 - Current]

City: Khairpur Mir's Country: Pakistan

Teaching Students of Cambridge Board and Agha Khan Board.

Trainer

World Youth Alliance Asia Pacific [10/01/2021 - Current]

City: Manila

Country: Philippines

Teaching short courses to International Students such as Certified Training Program and Advocacy Academy.

Tutor

Global Peace Institute London [01/07/2021 - 18/07/2021]

City: London

Country: United Kingdom

Taught at Global Kids Camp, students of fifty four countries joined the Camp.

Teacher

Noor Institute of of English language [01/05/2014 – 30/06/2016]

City: Shikarpur **Country:** Pakistan

Teaching students from 1st to 12th Grade Conducting group discussion classes Teaching study skills

Internee

World Youth Alliance Asia Pacific [10/09/2021 – 29/12/2021]

City: Manila

Country: Philippines

In these fours moths of Internship we worked with diverse group of Scholars, Learned about different health issues, programs and administration.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Masters Applied Linguistic

Universitas Diponegoro (UNDIP) [13/08/2021 – 27/06/2023]

Address: Jl. Prof. Sudarto No.13, Tembalang, Kec. Tembalang, Kota Semarang, Jawa Tengah 50275, Indonesia, 50275 Semarang (Indonesia)

Website: https://www.undip.ac.id/language/en/home

B.S English (Literature and Linguistic)

Shah Abdul Latif University [01/01/2017 - 25/03/2021]

Address: Old National Highway, Khairpur Mir's, 66020 Sindh, Pakistan, 66020 Khairpur (Pakistan)

Website: https://salu.edu.pk/

Intermediate (Pre-Medical)

C&S Govt, Degree College [08/01/2014 - 03/09/2016]

Address: Main Shikarpur-Sukkur College Road, Shikarpur, 78100, Sindh, 78100 Shikarpur (Pakistan)

Website: https://web.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100081548752667

Matric (Science)

Govt: (N) Shah Latif High School [01/06/2009 – 31/07/2014]

Address: Haji Latif Shah Road, Shikarpur, 78100, Pakistan, 78100 Shikarpur (Pakistan) **Website:** https://web.facebook.com/Govtshahlatifhighschoolshikarpur/?_rdc=1&_rdr

Certification in Information Technology (C.I.T)

Mehran Computer Centre [01/01/2012 – 30/06/2012]

Address: Govt: (N) Islamia High School Lakhi Gate Shikarpur, 78100, Sindh, 78100 Shikarpur (Pakistan)

Intermediate Grade Drawing

Directorate of Schools Education Larkano Region, Larkano [01/01/2012 - 27/08/2013]

Address: Govt: High School, Shikarpur, 78100, Sindh, 78100 Shikarpur (Pakistan)

Hardware

Hidaya Institute of Science and Technology [01/01/2014 - 26/05/2014]

Address: Hathidar Shikarpur, 78100, Hidaya Institute of Science and Technology, Sindh 78100 Shikarpur, 78100

Shikarpur (Pakistan)

Website: https://www.histpk.org/

Basic English Grammar

Hidaya Institute of Science and Technology [02/06/2014 – 24/07/2014]

Address: Hathidar Shikarpur, 78100, Hidaya Institute of Science and Technology, Sindh 78100 Shikarpur 78100

Shikarpur, Sindh, Pakistan, 78100 Shikarpur (Pakistan)

Website: https://www.histpk.org/

M.S Office

Hidaya Institute of Science and Technology [01/01/2015 - 25/05/2015]

Address: Hathidar Shikarpur, 78100, Hidaya Institute of Science and Technology, Sindh, 78100 Shikarpur

(Pakistan)

Website: https://www.histpk.org/

Compassion Integrity Training

Life University, Centre for Compassion, Integrity and Secular Ethics [01/06/2021 – 03/08/2021]

Address: 1269 Barclay Cir, Marietta, GA 30060, United States, 30060 Georgia (United States)

Website: http://www.compassion.life.edu/

Afro South Asia Emotional CPR

The Cell Lab Team [18/10/2021 – 26/10/2021]

Address: Social-Emotional Learning for peace and development, (India)

Website: https://www.thesellab.org/

MENTAL HEALTH E-COURSE for Asia Pacific 2.0

Y-PEER Asia Pacific Center [17/07/2021 - 21/08/2021]

Address: 167 Sukhumvit 21 Soi 3, Khlong Toei Nuea, Watthana, Bangkok 10110, Thailand 10110 Bangkok

Thailand, 10110 Bangkok (Thailand)

Website: https://ypeerap.org/ - https://drive.google.com/file/d/168xfqKZsQr7gj7HObXOLckSQDGEkzjxk/view?

usp=sharing

Regional Peer Education Academy 2.0

Y-PEER Asia Pacific Center [01/01/2021 - 12/02/2022]

Address: 167 Sukhumvit 21 Soi 3, Khlong Toei Nuea, Watthana, Bangkok 10110, Thailand 10110 Bangkok Thailand

, 10110 Bangkok (Thailand)
Website: https://ypeerap.org/

Certified Taring Program (CTP)

World Youth Alliance Asia Pacific [10/01/2021 – 31/03/2021]

Address: 323 Katipunan Ave, Quezon City, 1108 Metro Manila, Philippines, 1108 Manila (Philippines)

Website: https://www.wya.net/category/asia-pacific/

Advocacy Academy

World Youth Alliance Asia Pacific [01/05/2022 - 29/06/2022]

Address: 323 Katipunan Ave, Quezon City, 1108 Metro Manila, Philippines 1108 Manila Philippines, 1108 Manila

(Philippines)

Website: https://www.wya.net/category/asia-pacific/

Training of Trainers (TOT)

World Youth Alliance Asia Pacific [30/10/2021 - 15/11/2021]

Address: 323 Katipunan Ave, Quezon City, 1108 Metro Manila, Philippines 1108 Manila Philippines , 1108 Manila

(Philippines)

Website: https://www.wya.net/category/asia-pacific/

Business Sustainability "Challenges and Opportunity during Crisis Situation"

Faculty of Social and Political Science, Diponegoro University [01/09/2021 - 15/09/2021]

Address: Jl. Prof. Sudarto No.13, Tembalang, Kec. Tembalang, Kota Semarang, Jawa Tengah 50275, Indonesia, 50575 Jawa Tengah (Indonesia)

Website: https://www.undip.ac.id/language/en/home

ICYF 4th Diplomacy Academy

ICYF [11/06/2021 - 26/07/2021]

Address: Istanbul World Trade Center, A3 Block 7th floor, 34149, Yeşilköy, Istanbul/Turkey, 34149 Istanbul

(Türkiye)

Website: http://www.icyforum.org/ctertificate-verification/

Global Kids Camp

Global Peace Institute London and AIA-GESS Georgia [03/07/2021 - 18/07/2021]

Address: Global Peace Institute London, 5208 London (United Kingdom) Website: https://web.facebook.com/Globalpeaceinstitute/?_rdc=1&_rdr

AUA - UM International Academic Conference on Corpus Linguistics 2023 (Virtual Conference)

"New Trends in Language and Linguistics Studies" [24/11/2023 – 25/11/2023]

City: Universiti Malaya Country: Malaysia

Economics and Business International Camp and Courses for Sustainability (EBICCS) 2023

Faculty of Economic and Business Universitas Diponegoro [24/07/2023 - 11/08/2023]

City: Semarang **Country:** Indonesia

Website: https://io.undip.ac.id/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Sindhi

Other language(s):

English Urdu

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1 LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Microsoft/ Microsoft Office / Typing / Customer service Sales Leadership Public speaking Office administration / Team-work oriented / Effective team work / Ability To Work Under Pressure. / *Communication Skills / Organizational and Planning Skills / social worker

PUBLICATIONS

<u>Based on Natural Semantic Meta-Language (NSM) Theory an Analysis of "Marriage Cultural Lexicons" in the Urdu Language</u>

[2023]

https://twasp.info/journal/home

Sarfaraz Ali, Mualimin, M.Hum (2023). Based on Natural Semantic Meta-Language (NSM) Theory an

Analysis of "Marriage Cultural Lexicons" in the Urdu Language. North American Academic Research, 6(5), 45-50. doi:https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7963576

An Analysis of Urdu Nominal Phrases based on the Theory of X-bar

[2023]

https://rjllp.muet.edu.pk/index.php/repertus

Ali, S., & Dr. Mualimin, M.Hum. (2023). An Analysis of Urdu Nominal Phrases based on the Theory of X-bar. Repertus: Journal of Linguistics, Language Planning and Policy, 2(1), 26–36. Retrieved from https://rillp.muet.edu.pk/index.php/repertus/article/view/20

<u>Comparative analysis of phonological processes in English reading among Sindhi and English-speaking college learners.</u>

[2023]

Ali, S., & Subiyanto, A. . (2023). Comparative analysis of phonological processes in English reading among Sindhi and English-speaking college learners. Journal of Languages, Linguistics and Literary Studies , 3(3), 134-142. https://doi.org/10.57040/jllls.v3i3.510

The Importance of Education

[2022]

https://www.wya.net/op-ed/the-importance-of-education-2/

The article was written during final months of Internship at World Youth Alliance Asia Pacific

Link: https://www.wya.net/op-ed/the-importance-of-education-2/

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

Peace Talk and Dialogue Series at SALU

[Shah Abdul Latif University, Old National Highway, Khairpur Mir's, 66020 Sindh, 29/01/2020 – 01/02/2020]

Represented University as one of the best students and rewarded with the tittle of Peace Ambassador in Training on "Peace and Tolerance for Students Groups"

Link: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1kG9u1GSovWkn97-va0vPPIw5gty-R7RO/view?usp=sharing

Global Youth Peace Summit 2020

[10/07/2020 - 11/07/2020]

I had been selected among the 'Best 5 participants' (non-speaking) at the Global Youth Peace Summit (GGYPS 2020) organised by the Global Peace Institute (GPI) to become a 'GPI Youth Ambassador'. and awarded with Gold Medal, Pin and appreciation certificates.

Link: https://web.facebook.com/Globalpeaceinstitute/videos/310993396607609

Art Surge 2021- International Youth Day Conference

[Online, 28/08/2021 - 29/08/2021]

Participated in ART SURGE 2021 Conference conducted by Art SEA and Artdialogo Asia. Theme: "Reconnecting the Youth, Aspirations, and Cultures through Art in the New Normal".

Link: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1LaA0wz2yagiGNQCqtklSy65FOXeRIj79/view?usp=sharing

Citizens International Youth Summit 2020

[Online, 09/08/2020 - 12/08/2020]

Attended international Youth Summit as delegate of the Pakistan.

Link: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1umFBDcCRmgaMktyG4g2vET1WJ9ejGNPf/view?usp=sharing

International Youth Summit 22

[Online, 12/08/2021 - 15/08/2021]

Got an opportunity to represent Pakistan in a diverse group of, Scholars, Academician, and Researchers.

Link: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1zkoIVdOqsn8Slw155pXljexyW2HZ6oKx/view?usp=sharing

RECOMMENDATIONS

Associate Professor - Supervisor

Name: Dr. Mualimin Mualimin Phone number: (+62) 857407598040 Email: mualimin@lecturer.undip.ac.id

Supervisor in Masters program at Universitas Diponegoro, Semarang, Indonesia

Teacher

Name: Prof Dr Ghulam Mustafa Mashori Phone number: (+92) 3003135038 Email: gmustafa.mashori@salu.edu.pk

Teacher at University.

Teacher

Name: Shoukat Ali Lohar

Phone number: (+92) 3023368590 Email: Shoukat.ali@faculty.muet.edu.pk

Teacher at University

Teacher

Name: Rubina Shaheeen Arian Phone number: (+92) 3003444407 Email: drowsylaked eye@yahoo.com

Teacher at University. **Link:** https://salu.edu.pk/

Friend

Name: Syed Yaseen Shah

Phone number: (+92) 3443283473 Email: yaseensanamshah@gmail.com Friend, Colleague and Well wisher

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Gold Medal

Global Peace Institute London

I was selected among the 'Best 5 participants' (non-speaking) at the Global Youth Peace Summit (GGYPS 2020)

Link: https://web.facebook.com/Globalpeaceinstitute/videos/310993396607609

2nd Position in Annual Exam of XII

C&S Govt: Degree College [01/08/2016]

Got 2nd position in Pre-Exam of HSC Part-II (Pre-Medical) examination held in session 2015-2016

Link: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1NcjbnHE2HyUipd8n6TNluY7s4Q4-9w0d/view?usp=sharing

1st Position in Annual Examination SSC-II

Govt: (N) Shah Latif High School, Shikarpur, 78100, Sindh [14/05/2014]

The annual examination of Secondary School Certificate were held on May, 2014 and awarded with shield and certificate.

Link: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1q_Rg3NkjSL-gH4cl44eD2_gFmt2k5XZh/view?usp=sharing

1st Position in Speech Competition

Govt: (N) Shah Latif High School, Shikarpur, 78100, Sindh [27/01/2014]

Got 1st Position in Annual School Speech Competition

Link: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1wbMxVa7BeA7TFHRtK2aT6ZDPBw_qhQ5X/view?usp=sharing

2nd Position in Speech Competition

Deputy Commissioner District Shikarpur, Shikarpur, 78100, Sindh

Got 2nd Position in Intra District School School Students Competition 2015

Link: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1qqphBUq3R-nvaWyaAOn755kCUbXU-hIP/view?usp=sharing

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Reading Books, Newspapers and stories

Reading newspapers is one of my childhoods habits.

Link: https://www.dawn.com/

Social Work

In my spare/leisure time, I always try hard to engage in social activities.

VOLUNTEERING

Me For Myself (M4M) Volunteer Program 2021 (Batch II)

[167 Sukhumvit 21 Soi 3, Khlong Toei Nuea, Watthana, Bangkok 10110, 01/05/2021 – 30/08/2021]

Me For Myself (M4M) Volunteer Program 2021 (Batch II) for a duration of three months from May-August 2021. During the volunteer program, the volunteer has shown commendable contribution & enthusiasms or advocacy on mental health and well-being.

The campaign is an online initiative to raise awareness on mental health and well-being especially during the COVID-19 pandemic organized by Y-PEER Asia Pacific Center, with the support from UNFPA Asia Pacific Regional Office and RCF.

Link: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1g|1KmygPfazb-lK9|fPZUTGFrCEqfR8M/view?usp=sharing

As a peace-loving person, I try to create harmony wherever I go. It is my greatest wish to explore different cultures, education systems, and lifestyles of the people. As a representative of the youth, my exposure to all the cultures and lifestyles would help in removing any misconceptions.

Sikarpur 78100, Sindh, Pakistan, 31/12/2023

Barrack

Sarfaraz Ali